Finding Aid for John and Leni Sinclair Papers 1957-2003
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
- Visual Materials
  - Photographs
    - Ann Arbor Sun/The Sun
      - Photographer files
        - Miscellaneous photographers; negatives only
          - Prazzato, Jan
            - Street gangs, Keith Harvey (Box 42)
          - Reid, John
            - Moses Baldwin, guardhouse, Detroit police (Box 42)
          - Savely? (Box 42)
        - Miscellaneous photographers; negatives and contact sheets
          - Beyer, Bob
            - Crater busts (Box 42)
          - Gould, Hal
            - Mondale 10/76 (Box 42)
          - Jim
            - Dig in, police on Diag (Box 42)
            - Third park concert (Box 42)
            - Free concert, 3rd, people dancing (Box 42)
          - Kagan, Steve
            - McDonalds 7/75 (Box 42)
          - Kooar, Joe
            - Schiller Hall 11/75 (Box 42)
          - Pomanski, Tom
            - Narcs, Gary Starkweather 2/75 (Box 42)
          - Rappaport
            - Ann Arbor art galleries 6/75 (Box 42)
            - Pizza Bob's, Eden's, Baobab, Lobster (Box 42)
          - Weissman, David
            - Ozone '73 (Box 42)
          - Zaret, Eli
            - Colburn at City Council 3/1974 (Box 42)
  - Posters and broadsides, etc
    The Posters and broadsides, etc. series includes the ground-breaking concert posters designed for Rainbow productions by Gary Grimshaw as well as more recent concert and poetry performance posters.
    - Concert posters
      - Classical (Box 43)
      - Grimshaw, Gary (artist)
        - Pisces Eyes (Box 43)
        - Rainbow Graphics and RPP (Box 43)
        - Trans-Love (Box 43)
        - Miscellaneous (Box 43)
      - Ozone (Box 43)
      - Rainbow Productions and RPP (except Grimshaw) (Box 43)
      - Strata (Box 43)
      - Trans-Love (Box 43)
      - UAC (Box 43)
        (not otherwise identified)
      - Miscellaneous artists (Box 43)
      - Unidentified artists (Box 43)
    - Album cover art, newspaper and music advertising, etc (Box 44)
    - Dance concert posters and miscellaneous
      - Grimshaw, Gary (artist) (Box 44)
      - Miscellaneous artists (Box 44)
      - Drawings and paintings (Box 44)
      - Photographs (outsize) (Box 44)
      - Poetry (broadsheets and posters) (Box 44)
    - Political posters
      - Grimshaw, Gary, and other Rainbow Graphics artists (Box 44)
      - Miscellaneous artists (Box 44)
    - Music and poetry advertising posters 1980s-1990s (Box 44)
  - Videocassettes
    Videocassettes include a videotape of Sinclair's poetry performances, as well as videotapes related to marijuana reform.
    - Sinclair Poetry reading with Jim Gustafson, Mick Vranich, and "Pat" (Box 74)
    - John Sinclair and the Traverse City Blues Scholars, Traverse City, MI July, 1997 (Box 74)
    - "The 11th Annual High Times Cannabis Cup Video-Starring John Sinclair and the Blues Scholars," 1999 (Box 74)
    - "The War On Us" 1999 (Box 74)
      (legalization of marijuana for medical use video)
  - Videotapes
    The series consists of open-reel (EIAJ) tapes of the 1973 Ann Arbor Jazz and Blues Festival and of an Allied Artists Association (AAA) Jazz Center Conference in Detroit.
    - 1973 Ann Arbor Jazz and Blues Festival Videotapes
      Along with Peter Andrews, Sinclair revived the pioneering Ann Arbor Blues Festival in 1972 after a one-year hiatus. They expanded the festival's lineup and rechristened it the Ann Arbor Jazz and Blues Festival. Portions of the 1973 festival were recorded on EIAJ open-reel videotape. The tapes came to the library with the warning that" they might have one play in them." In 2009 the tapes were digitized by a professional video lab. Master Beta SP tapes were made along with high resolution (mpeg2) and streaming files and DVD use copies. The quality of the video is generally good, though lighting and other factors sometimes affect the quality. Some tapes exhibit "snow" or other distortions at the beginning of a reel, but this usually last less than a minute. The audio (taken from the broadcast feed of U-M radio station WUOM) is generally very good.
      The library does not have artist release or music publisher releases for any of the performers. The DVD copies are available for use in the library, but cannot be duplicated or distributed at this time.
      - Mojo Boogie/Leon Thomas (Pt. I) 1973, 850-1-1
        - Original:, open reel videotape, b/w, sound, 01:03:16
        - Use Copy:, 1 optical disks DVDs (Box 9)
      - Leon Thomas (Pt. II)/ Freddie King (Pt. I) 1973, 850-2-2
        - Original:, open reel videotape, b/w, sound, 01:03:29
        - Use Copy:, 1 optical disks DVDs (Box 9)
      - Freddie King (Pt. II)/ Brooklyn Blues Busters 1973, 850-3-3
        - Original:, open reel videotape, b/w, sound, 01:03:17
        - Use Copy:, 1 optical disks DVDs (Box 9)
      - Detroit Blues (Pt. I) 1973, 850-4-4
        - Original:, open reel videotape, b/w, sound, 01:03:25
        - Use Copy:, 1 optical disks DVDs (Box 9)
      - Detroit Blues (Pt. II) 1973, 850-5-5
        - Original:, open reel videotape, b/w, sound, 00:59:30
        - Use Copy:, 1 optical disks DVDs (Box 9)
      - Detroit Blues (Pt. III) 1973, 850-6-6
        - Original:, open reel videotape, b/w, sound, 00:36:42
        - Use Copy:, 1 optical disks DVDs (Box 9)
      - Motor City Blues 1973, 850-7-7
        - Original:, open reel videotape, b/w, sound, 00:58:00
        - Use Copy:, 1 optical disks DVDs (Box 9)
      - CJQ Dub #1 1973, 850-8-8
        - Original:, open reel videotape, b/w, sound, 00:39:55
        - Use Copy:, 1 optical disks DVDs (Box 9)
      - CJQ, John Lee Hooker 1973, 850-9-9
        - Original:, open reel videotape, b/w, sound, 00:57:12
        - Use Copy:, 1 optical disks DVDs (Box 9)
      - Charles Mingus 1973, 850-10-10
        - Original:, open reel videotape, b/w, sound, 00:42:37
        - Use Copy:, 1 optical disks DVDs (Box 9)
      - Jimmy Reed 1973, 850-11-11
        - Original:, open reel videotape, b/w, sound, 00:23:56
        - Use Copy:, 1 optical disks DVDs (Box 9)
      - Big Walter Horton/Jimmy Lee's Band 1973, 850-12-12
        - Original:, open reel videotape, b/w, sound, 01:03:18
        - Use Copy:, 1 optical disks DVDs (Box 9)
      - Johnny Otis Show (Pt. I) 1973, 850-13-13
        - Original:, open reel videotape, b/w, sound, 01:03:20
        - Use Copy:, 1 optical disks DVDs (Box 9)
      - Johnny Otis Show (Pt. II) 1973, 850-14-14
        - Original:, open reel videotape, b/w, sound, 00:32:40
        - Use Copy:, 1 optical disks DVDs (Box 9)
      - Infinite Sound/King Biscuit Boys (Pt.I) 1973, 850-15-15
        - Original:, open reel videotape, b/w, sound, 01:03:24
        - Use Copy:, 1 optical disks DVDs (Box 9)
      - King Biscuit Boys (Pt. II), Victoria Spivey 1973, 850-16-16
        - Original:, open reel videotape, b/w, sound, 00:54:54
        - Use Copy:, 1 optical disks DVDs (Box 9)
      - Mime troupe/Luther Allison (Pt. I) 1973, 850-17-17
        - Original:, open reel videotape, b/w, sound, 01:01:46
        - Use Copy:, 1 optical disks DVDs (Box 9)
      - Luther Allison (Pt. II) 1973, 850-18-18
        - Original:, open reel videotape, b/w, sound, 00:25:18
        - Use Copy:, 1 optical disks DVDs (Box 9)
      - Hound Dog Taylor (Pt. II), Mighty Joe Young (Pt. I) 1973, 850-19-19
        - Original:, open reel videotape, b/w, sound, 00:32:54
        - Use Copy:, 1 optical disks DVDs (Box 9)
      - Mighty Joe Young (Pt. II), Otis Rush and Homesick James 1973, 850-20-20
        - Original:, open reel videotape, b/w, sound, 00:33:19
        - Use Copy:, 1 optical disks DVDs (Box 9)
      - Mighty Joe Young (Pt. III) 1973, 850-21-21
        - Original:, open reel videotape, b/w, sound, 00:32:36
        - Use Copy:, 1 optical disks DVDs (Box 9)
      - Lucille Spann Interview 1973, 850-22-22
        - Original:, open reel videotape, b/w, sound, 00:27:49
        - Use Copy:, 1 optical disks DVDs (Box 9)
      - T.B.D. 1973, 850-23-23
        - Original:, open reel videotape, b/w, sound, 00:32:12
        - Use Copy:, 1 optical disks DVDs (Box 9)
      - Unidentified 1973, 850-24-24
        - Original:, open reel videotape, b/w, sound, 00:33:05
        - Use Copy:, 1 optical disks DVDs (Box 9)
    - Allied Artists Association (AAA) Jazz Center Conference
      - VO25.06M, Counselor Tech. Tr., 19780823, 850-26-1
        - Original:, open reel videotape, b/w, sound, 01:00:30
        - Use Copy:, 1 optical disks DVDs (Box 9)
      - VO25.07M August 20, 1978, 850-27-2
        - Original:, open reel videotape, b/w, sound, 01:01:10
        - Use Copy:, 1 optical disks DVDs (Box 9)
      - VO25.08M August 20, 1978, 850-28-3
        - Original:, open reel videotape, b/w, sound, 01:01:45
        - Use Copy:, 1 optical disks DVDs (Box 9)
      - VO25.09M May 16, 1978, 850-29-4
        - Original:, open reel videotape, b/w, sound, 01:01:01
        - Use Copy:, 1 optical disks DVDs (Box 9)
      - VO25.10M May 16, 1978, 850-30-5
        - Original:, open reel videotape, b/w, sound, 01:01:07
        - Use Copy:, 1 optical disks DVDs (Box 9)
      - VO25.11M May 16, 1978, 850-31-6
        - Original:, open reel videotape, b/w, sound, 01:01:46
        - Use Copy:, 1 optical disks DVDs (Box 9)
      - VO25.12M May 30, 1978, 850-32-7
        - Original:, open reel videotape, b/w, sound, 01:01:08
        - Use Copy:, 1 optical disks DVDs (Box 9)
      - VO25.13M May 30, 1978, 850-33-8
        - Original:, open reel videotape, b/w, sound, 01:01:14
        - Use Copy:, 1 optical disks DVDs (Box 9)
      - VO25.14M May 30, 1978, 850-34-9
        - Original:, open reel videotape, b/w, sound, 01:01:30
        - Use Copy:, 1 optical disks DVDs (Box 9)
- Post-2000 Activities and Projects
  The series is unprocessed.
  - Audio-Visual
    - CDs (Box 75)
    - CDs (Box 76)
    - Audio-cassettes (Box 77)
    - Reel-to-reel tapes (Box 77)
    - VHS videotapes (Box 78)
  - Project files
    - "Fattening Frogs for Snakes" project file (Box 79)
    - Miscellaneous drafts, projects, and e-mail (Box 80)
Index to Underground Newspapers in Sinclair Collection
The underground newspapers in this collection include primarily papers containing articles by or about John Sinclair and the White Panther Party. Papers published in Michigan have been removed and added to the Michigan Historical Commission's Michigan underground press collection.
Pre-1978 Publications
And Fort Worth, Texas (1 issue, Box 26)
The Avalanche Magazine Berkeley, California (1 issue, Box 33)
Beach Blanket Struggle (or Beach Blanket News) Miami Beach, Florida (3 issues, Box 33)
Berkeley Tribe Berkeley, California. (2 issues, Box 26,33)
Black Fire Washington, D.C. (1 issue, Box 36)
The Black Panther San Francisco, Cal. (4 issues, Box 26,33)
Blues Power Varese, Italy (2 issues, Box 36)
Blues Unlimited Bexhill-on-Sea, Eng. (2 issues, Box 36)
Broadside and the Free Press Cambridge, Mass. (1 issue, Box 33)
Buddy Dallas, Texas (1 issue, Box 36)
Bull Weevil Toledo, Ohio (1 par. issue, Box 33)
Burning River News Cleveland, Ohio (2 issues, Box 26)
Can o' Beans Lincoln, Nebraska (2 issues, Box 26)
Changes New York (3 issues, Box 26,33)
Chapter (Abbey Wood White Panthers) London, England (1 issue, Box 33)
Chicago Seed Chicago 53 iss. issues, Box 35)
Crawdaddy New York (4 issues, Box 26)
Crystal City News Bowling Green, Ohio (2 issues, Box 33)
Dallas Notes Dallas, Texas (2 issues, Box 33)
Douglas Comix New York (1 issue, Box 26)
Earth Island Chicago, Illinois (1 issue, Box 26)
The East Village Other New York 35 iss. issues, Box 26,34)
Electric Frog Richland, Washington (1 issue, Box 36)
Exit Bowling Green, Ohio (1 issue, Box 26)
Extra Providence, RI (6 issues, Box 26,33)
Flavor Roslyn, New York (1 issue, Box 26)
Free City News (Illinois White Panthers) Chicago, IL (1 issue, Box 26)
The Free Ranger Tribe Presents UPS News Service New York (2 issues, Box 26,33)
Fusion Boston, Mass. (1 issue, Box 33)
Gay Power New York (2 issues, Box 33)
Georgia Straight Vancouver, B.C.,Canada (2 issues, Box 26,33)
Head New York (1 issue, Box 26)
Hotcha! Zurich, Switzerland (17 iss. issues, Box 26,36)
I'm All Right Pittsburgh, Pa. (1 issue, Box 33)
Kaleidoscope Milwaukee, Wisconsin (1 issue, Box 33)
Liberated Guardian New York (1 issue, Box 26)
Living Blues Chicago (5 issues, Box 26)
Logos Montreal, Quebec, Can. (1 issue, Box 33)
Los Angeles Free Press Los Angeles, Cal. (1 issue, Box 33)
The Marijuana Review Mill Valley, Cal. (5 issues, Box 26)
Metropolitan Review New York (1 issue, Box 26)
The Modern Utopian Berkeley, Cal. (1 issue, Box 26)
Mojo Entmooter Fairfax, Cal. (1 issue, Box 36)
Movement San Francisco, Cal. (1 issue, Box 33)
Nola Express New Orleans, La. (3 issues, Box 33)
Notes from Underground San Francisco, Cal. (1 issue, Box 26)
The Oracle San Francisco, Cal. (1 issue, Box 33)
The Oracle of Southern California Los Angeles, Cal. (4 issues, Box 33)
Orpheus Phoenix, Arizona (2 issues, Box 33)
Other Scenes New York (2 issues, Box 33)
Oz London, England (1 issue, Box 33)
The Park Press North Baltimore, Ohio (1 issue, Box 33)
The Phoenix Boston, Mass. (2 issues, Box 27)
Plain Dealer Philadelphia, Pa. (1 issue, Box 33)
Prairie Sun Peoria, Illinois (1 issue, Box 36)
Queen City Express Cincinnati, Ohio (1 issue, Box 33)
Quicksilver Times Washington, D.C. (17 issues, Box 34)
The Rag Austin, Texas (1 issue, Box 33)
Rainbow Nation News Baltimore, Md. (1 issue, Box 33)
Rat New York (4 issues, Box 33)
Red Balloon Stony Brook, NY (1 issue, Box 33)
Rising Up Angry Chicago, Illinois (1 issue, Box 33)
River City Review Memphis, Tennessee (1 issue, Box 33)
Rock New York (1 issue, Box 27)
Rock-Roll-News Fremont, Ohio (1 issue, Box 36)
Rolling Stone San Francisco, Cal. (4 issues, Box 27)
Soul Bag Paris, France (1 issue, Box 27)
Sounds Köln, W. Germany (2 issues, Box 27)
Southern Flyer Dunedin, New Zealand (1 issue, Box 27)
Space City! Houston, Texas (1 issue, Box 33)
The Spectator Bloomington, Indiana (1 issue, Box 33)
Spokane Natural Spokane, Washington (1 issue, Box 33)
The Staff Los Angeles, Cal. (1 issue, Box 27)
Stop the Trial! Chicago, Illinois (1 issue, Box 33)
Subterranean Homesick News Long Beach, Cal. (1 issue, Box 33)
Sun Rise Macomb, Illinois (11 issues, Box 27)
Take Over Madison, Wisconsin (2 issues, Box 33)
Terminal City Express Vancouver, B.C.,Can. (2 issues, Box 33)
Touch (Marin White Panthers) Corte Madera, Cal. (3 issues, Box 33)
Tracks Bloomfield Hills, Mich. (1 issue, Box 27)
Truckin' On (Macomb White) Panthers) Macomb, Illinois (14 issues, Box 33)
Underground Press Digest New York (1 issue, Box 27)
Underground Press Syndicate Directory Phoenix, Arizona (1 issue, Box 33)
University Review New York (2 issues, Box 27)
War Behind Walls San Francisco, Cal. (1 issue, Box 33)
White Trash (West London White Panthers) London, England (1 issue, Box 33)
Yipster Times New York (3 issues, Box 33)
Zygote New York (1 issue, Box 27)
1978-1999 Publications
Agenda, Ann Arbor (1 issue, Box 57)
Big Chair, ? (1 issue, Box 57)
Blue Suede News, Duval, WA (1 issue, Box 57)
Carbon 14, Philadelphia, PA (2 issue, Box 57)
Discoveries, ? (1 issue, Box 57)
Do the Pop, Seattle, WA (1 issue, Box 57)
Free Fest Monthly, Chicago, IL (1 issue, Box 57)
Freakout U.S.A., Seattle, WA (2 issue, Box 57)
Goldmine, ? (1 issue, Box 57)
HighTimes, ? (1 issue, Box 57)
Indie, New Orleans, LA (1 issue, Box 57)
Jam Rag, ? (1 issue, Box 57)
Mojo, London, England (1 issue, Box 57)
Music Magazine (Japanese), Japan (1 issue, Box 57)
Next (SoCal Words and Voices), Los Angeles, CA(1 issue, Box 57)
New Orleans Pos, New Orleans, LA (1 issue, Box 57)
RPM, Southfield, MI (3 issue, Box 57)
Slam, Athens, GA (2 issue, Box 57)
Select Index to Correspondents
Bursley, Gilbert E., 1913-
June 17, 1971; July 30, 1971; and Aug. 5, 1971
Davis, Rennie, 1940-
Dec. 12, 1971
Ginsberg, Allen, 1926-
Sept. 14, 1969; Sept. 23, 1969; Oct. 5, 1969; Oct. 17, 1969; Oct. 12, 1970; Feb. 6, 1971; and Nov. 17, 1971
Hart, Philip Aloysius, 1912-1976
Oct. 23, 1969; and Oct. 5, 1971
Hoffman, Abbie
Sept. ?, 1969; Sept. 15, 1969; May 1, 1970; and undated (pseudonym George Metefsky)
Leary, Timothy, 1920-
Dec. 9, 1969; Dec. 14, 1969; Dec. 13, 1970
Rubin, Jerry
Sept. 4, 1971
Vaughn, Jackie III
July 20, 1971; July 25, 1971; Oct. 28, 1971; Nov. 7, 1971; and Nov. 22, 1971